<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resumes on Devops Discoveries</title>
    <link>https://clinta.github.io/resume/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resumes on Devops Discoveries</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>clint@clintarmstrong.net (Clint Armstrong)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>clint@clintarmstrong.net (Clint Armstrong)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://clinta.github.io/resume/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Résumé</title>
      <link>https://clinta.github.io/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clint@clintarmstrong.net (Clint Armstrong)</author>
      <guid>https://clinta.github.io/resume/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;clint-armstrong&#34;&gt;Clint Armstrong&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;work-experience&#34;&gt;Work Experience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;01/2015 - Present&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Network Administrator&lt;/strong&gt; Trillium Staffing, Kalamazoo, MI&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;Primary technical resource for managing Networking, Servers and cloud
 services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built a full mesh DMVPN network between over 100 branch offices using
Linux on commodity hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managed a Citrix environment providing desktops for over 200 users.
Handled upgrades between several major version of both Citrix and Windows
Server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built a modern container cluster for running services on Linux.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Migrated communications services from on premis Microsoft Exchange and
Sharepoint to Office 365.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built a &lt;a href=&#34;diy-sbs-for-Office-365-Unified-Messaging&#34;&gt;solution&lt;/a&gt; for
integrating Office 365 Unified Messaging using open source software.  and
Cisco Unified Communications with only open source software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Handled upgrades of multiple clusters between major versions of Vmware
Vsphere.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Handled a migration between physical datacenters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Migrated from provider IP space to BGP peering with multiple providers
using provider independant IPs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrote and contributed multiple modules for SaltStack to manage our linux
servers and workstations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrote multiple docker plugins to built our container cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;12/2011 - 01/2015&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Professional Services Engineer&lt;/strong&gt; Secant Techologies, Kalamazoo, MI&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;Provided services to customers including NetPro visits to check health of
 network and server and leading upgrade projects to server infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frequent repairs of unhealthy Active Directory infrastructure including
correcting AD Site topology, forcibly removing failed domain controllers,
and troubleshooting and repairing DNS and DHCP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many implementations of multi-host VSphere deployments with iSCSI, Fibre
Chanel and SAS based shared storage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sole engineer on many server virtualization and upgrade projects for
Active Directory versions 2008R2 and 2012, Exchange 2010 and 2013,
various version of Microsoft SQL and other line of business applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engaged in long term support for a large company coordinating migrations
to accommodate a corporate acquisition. Included Exchange and Active
Directory migrations, workstation inventory and replacement, and user
support coordination.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;01/2011 - 12/2011&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft Systems Administrator&lt;/strong&gt; Liberty University, Lynchburg, VA&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;Primary Administrator responsible for design and maintenance of Active
 Directory, Exchange, Active Directory Federation Services, Forefront
 Unified Access Gateway and Public Key Infrastructure&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lead technician in project to migrate from an on-premises Exchange 2007
environment to a hybrid oexistent deployment with 350,000 student user
accounts in the cloud on Microsoft Office 365 and 000 Faculty and Staff
accounts in on-premises Exchange 2010.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented Forefront Unified Access Gateway to secure external
authentication to Sharepoint and ther internal web services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented Active Directory Federation Services to provide single sign
on for several external ervices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participated in implementation PCI security requirements for storage of
sensitive data on infrastructure servers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;2008 - 2011&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Desktop Configuration Administrator&lt;/strong&gt; Liberty University, Lynchburg, VA&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;Managed the centeralized configuration of over 5000 workstations across
 campus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented and managed Microsoft System Center Configuration Manager
2007 for management of over 5000 workstations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented Microsoft Windows Deployment Services with a custom front-end
to provide PXE booting and advanced automated imaging workflows to
increase productivity for On-Site Support Technicians.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repackaged and made the university software library available for
installation via SCCM or Group Policy, improving efficiency for support
departments by allowing self-service installations for users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created and maintained operating system images for Windows XP, Windows
Vista and Windows 7.   Created and maintained Active Directory Group
Policies for workstations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managed Windows Updates for workstations via Windows Server Update
Services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automated repetitive business processes and client operations with
VBScript and PowerShell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participated in committees coordinating the implementation of Information
Technology Infrastructure Library (ITIL) business process throughout IT.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;2008&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Desk-Side Support Technician&lt;/strong&gt; Liberty University, Lynchburg, VA&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;Provided desk side support for escalated IT tickets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operated as top-tier technical support troubleshooting hardware, software
and network issues which ould not be solved by remote support
technicians.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deployed and re-imaged workstations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;2005 - 2007&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IT Technician&lt;/strong&gt; Comstock Public Schools, Kalamazoo, MI&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remote and on-site support technician&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created and maintained operating system images for Windows 98 and Windows
XP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managed software deployment via Novell Zenworks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provided remote and on-site technical support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-source-projects&#34;&gt;Open Source Projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TrilliumIT/undocker-dns&#34;&gt;undocker-dns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;A small daemon to keep Docker from changing the dns server in a container.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TrilliumIT/docker-vxlan-plugin&#34;&gt;docker-vxlan-plugin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;A plugin for connecting docker containers to vxlan overlay networks.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TrilliumIT/docker-arp-ipam&#34;&gt;docker-arp-ipam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;A docker IPAM plugin to assign IP addresses to containers based on which
 addresses are already in use on the network.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TrilliumIT/docker-drouter&#34;&gt;docker-drouter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Co-Authored a tool which monitors docker containers and manipulates their
 routing tables to facilitate efficient routing between containers on a
 cluster of hosts.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/saltstack/salt/commits?author=clinta&#34;&gt;SaltStack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Wrote the
 &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.saltstack.com/en/latest/ref/states/all/salt.states.x509.html&#34;&gt;x509&lt;/a&gt;
 state and module which facilitates managing an internal x509 PKI with Salt.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TrilliumIT/docker-zfs-plugin&#34;&gt;docker-zfs-plugin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Wrote the go zfs library which this project is based on, and Setup the
 continuous integration pipeline.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;technologies-used&#34;&gt;Technologies Used&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technologies I have experinece with include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linux, Ubuntu, FreeBSD, FreeNAS, ZFS, Windows Server, Go (GoLang), Python,
PowerShell, Bash, Docker, Cisco, BGP, OSPF, Bird, Kamailio, Microsoft Exchange,
Windows Server, Office 365&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>